Damilare Oyedeji

Software Developer

SUMMARY

A talented and performance-driven Software Developer, with extensive education and experience in web development. Quick learner, ready for the latest technologies and confident when faced with challenges. I've worked on numerous projects from front-end to back-end (all available to view in my portfolio website). My knowledge and problem solving skills can be a great addition to any engineering team.

SKILLS

PROFICIENT: JavaScript, HTML, CSS, RaactJs, ContextAPI, Redux, TailwindCSS, Styled-Components, Git/GitHub, Bitbucket, Azure

EXPOSURE: NodeJs, ExpressJs, MongoDB.

PROFESSIONAL SKILLS: Leadership, Problem Solving, Communication, Teamwork.

CONTACT INFO:

Telephone: +2347031203859 Email: damoye81@gmail.com

LinkedIn:

http://linkedin.com/in/damilareoyedeji Github: https://github.com/Fuglydami Portfolio: https://fuglydami.surge.sh/ Lagos, Nigeria.

EMPLOYMENT

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

First Bank of Nigeria PLC. | July 2021 - PRESENT

- My role requires building stable and maintainable codebase using React
- Collaborate with the Agile team to ensure products were efficient and technically sound.
- Working directly with client stakeholders to developer technical solutions fir business cases.
- Leveraging responsive web frameworks to complete deliverables ahead of schedule.

FRONTEND ENGINEER

Digiscript Tech Solution. | March 2021-July 2021

- My role requires using best practices to build out reusable React components.
- Collaborate with Product Designers, Product Managers ans Software Engineers to deliver compelling user-facing products
- Build and improve clients websites, web apps and many other products for all browsers, devices using React workflow and other tools like styled-components, TailwindCSS and so on

FRONTEND DEVELOPER

Netpacks LTD. | Jan 2020 - Feb 2021

- Translated designs and wireframes into high-quality code and wrote application interface code via JavaScript following ReactJs workflow
- Developing features to enhance the user experience
- Collaborating with back-end engineers and designers to improve user experience-

ACADEMIC BACKGROUND

BACHELOR OF COMPUTER SCIENCE

National open university nigeria | 2014-2019

THE COMPLETE WEB DEVELOPER IN 2020 (UDEMY)
Zero to mastery academy | 2020

REACT TUTORIAL AND PROJECT COURSE (UDEMY)
John Smilga React Course | 2020-2021

PROJECTS

CENTRAL ADMIN DASHBOARD

An admin dashboard built for the subsidiaries of First Bank of Nigeria to provide support for it mobile app.

- -Portal was entirely built with Reactjs.
- -Implemented Json web Token for the authentication.
- -Used the AES.js package to encrypt the request payload being pasted to the endpoint.

COMFY SLOTH ECOMMERCE WEBSITE

An e-commerce website that sells a wide range of furnitures.

- Created front-end using React and Context API
- Integrated Auth0 to add a login/logout feature which saves your cart data. Google/github sign-in was also added so people that had google or github account could sign-in without registery
- -Integrated stripe to add a checkout feature that allows that customer to purchase items

GITHUB USERS SEARCH

A web app that fetches github users information off github API

- -Made the front-end using React and context API
- -Also Integrated Auth0 to add a login/logout features Used fusion charts API to display most used Programming languages, most stared Repo and most forked.

Refer to my portfolio for more.